EVILZRR
----FOR THE FIRST TIME TO MAKE A SUBTITLE-----
这个故事描述的是 ...  我是怎么死的.
This is the story of how I died.
别紧张, 实际上这是一个 非常有趣的故事
严格说来, 我根本不是故事的主角.
Don't worry, this is actually a very fun story.
And the truth is, it isn't even mine.
这是一个女孩的故事, 她名叫 "长发姑娘" ( Rapunzel )
This is the story of a girl named,
Rapunzel.
故事要从 "太阳" 开始讲起
And it starts, with the sun.
很久很久以前,
有一天, 从天空落下一缕阳光
Now, once upon a time, a single
drop of sunlight fell from the heavens.
从这一抹阳光里, 开出一朵 神奇金色的花朵
And from this small drop of sun,
grew a magic, golden, flower.
它有能力医治 生病及受伤的人们
It had the ability to heal the sick,
and injured.
哦, 看到个老妇人了嘛？
Oh, you see that old woman,
over there?
麻烦请记住这个人
You might want to remember her.
故事中, 她还满重要的...
She's kind of important.
然后, 几百年过去了, 不远处, 诞生了一个王国
Well, centuries pass and a hop
skip and a boat ride away there grew a kingdom.
王国 由人民爱戴的国王和王后 统治着
The kingdom was ruled by a beloved
King and Queen.
有天, 王后怀孕了, 但
And the Queen, well she was about
to have a baby,
她却生了病
and she got sick,
病的很严重
really, sick.
她的时间不多了
She was running out of time.
而就在那个时候, 大家就开始去寻找 "奇?"
And that's when people usually start
to look for a miracle.
也就是去寻找那朵... 神奇的金色花.
Or in this case, a magic golden flower.
唉唉, 我告诉过你们, 她很重要的,
Ahhh, I told you she'd
be important.
她并没和别人 共享着太阳的礼物,
You see instead of sharing the
suns gift,
这个女人, 女巫 "葛朵", 独占着金花
this woman, Mother Gothel,
hoarded its healing power
并用金花的魔力保持年轻, 达数百年之久 ..
and used it to keep herself
young for hundreds of years.
她只要, 唱一首特殊的歌曲
And all she had to do,
was sing a special song.
*花儿闪亮发光, 让你的力量闪耀*
*Flower gleam and glow,
let your power shine*
*使时光倒转, 带回曾经的我*
*Make the clock reverse,
bring back what once was mine*
*曾经是我的*
*What once was mine*
懂了吧, 她一唱歌就变年轻了, 有点怪, 对不对？
All right, you get the jist. She sings
to it, she turns young, creepy, right?
我们找到了！
We've found it!
神奇的金色花, 治愈了皇后
The magic of the golden flower,
healed the queen.
一个健康的女婴, 一位公主诞生了
A healthy baby girl,
a princess was born.
她有着美丽的金色头发
With beautiful golden hair.
给你一个提示
I'll give you a hint.
她就是长发姑娘
That's Rapunzel.
为了庆祝她的诞生, 国王和王后放出了天灯
To celebrate her birth, the King and
Queen launched a flying lantern into the sky.
从那一刻起, 一切都非常的完美
And for that one moment,
everything was perfect.
但幸福时刻, 却要结束了
And then that moment ended.
*花儿, 闪亮和发光, 让你的力量闪耀*
*Flower, gleam and glow,
let your powers shine*
*使时光重新..*   ....  喔！
*Make the clock re...*
HUH!
女巫葛朵闯入城堡, 偷走了孩子, 就这样 ... 走了
Gothel broke into the castle,stole the child, and just like that... gone.
全国人民到处寻找, 但他们无法找到公主.
The Kingdom searched and searched,
but they could not find the Princess.
但是, 在森林深处, 在一个隐藏的塔中
For deep within the forest In a hidden tower.
女巫 "葛朵" 独自抚养那孩子
Gothel raised the child
as her own.
**...带回消失了, 曾经是我的, 曾经是我的.*
*...bring what has been lost, bring back what
once was mine, what once was mine.*
女巫葛朵找到了 新的魔法花
Gothel had found her new magic flower.
但是这一次, 她决心独占着这个魔法
But this time she was determined
to keep it hidden.
为什么我不能到外面去？
Why can't I go outside?
外面的世界是一个危险的地方
The outside world is a dangerous place.
充满了可怕的, 自私的人
Filled with horrible, selfish people.
你必须呆在这里, 这里是安全的, 你明白吗, 花儿？-- 是的, 妈妈
- You must stay here, where you're safe.Do you understand, flower?- Yes, Mommy.
但, 塔的墙壁, 是不能遮盖住一切的
But the walls of that tower,could not hide everything.
每年她的生日, 国王和王后释放数以千计的天灯
Each year on her birthday, the King and Queen released thousands of lanterns into the sky.
希望有一天, 他们失去的公主, 能够返回家中
In hope that one day, their lost Princess, would return.
哈！
HAH!
嗯, 我想帕斯卡.. 应该没有躲藏在这里
Hmm, Well I guess Pascal's
not hiding out here.
找到你了！
GOTCHA!
我得 二十二分了
That's twenty two for me.
要不要改成45战, 23胜？
How about twenty three,
out of forty five?
好吧, 你想干什么？
Okay, well, what do you want to do?
不行, 我不这么认为
Yeah, I don't think so.
我喜欢待在这 你也是
I like it in here and so do you.
哦, 来吧, 帕斯卡, 待在这没啥不好
Oh, come on Pascal, it's
not so bad in there.
*上午7时 通常的节目安排*
*7a.m. the usual morning line-up*
*开始打扫, 直到所有的地面清洁*
*Start on the chores I sweep
'til the floors all clean.*
*抛光和打蜡, 洗衣服和拖地到发亮*
*Polish and wax, do laundry and
mop and shine up.*
*再扫一遍, 届时它才7:15*
*Sweep again, and by then
it's like 7:15.*
*所以, 我要读本书, 或者两本或三本*
*So I'll read a book,
or maybe two or three.*
*我会添加了一些新的画到我的画廊*
*Ill add a few new paintings
to my gallery.*
*基本上我会弹吉他, 针织, 做饭*
*I'll play guitar, and knit, and cook
and basically.*
*只是我的人生将不知何时...展开*
*Just wonder when will my
life, begin.*
*午餐后, 玩拼图, 飞镖和烘烤*
*Then after lunch, it's puzzles,
and darts and baking.*
*纸黏土, 跳点芭蕾, 国际象棋*
*Papier-mch? a bit of ballet,
and chess.*
*陶器, 说腹语, 做蜡烛*
*Pottery, and ventriloquy, candle making.*
*然后我就舒展, 也许画草图 爬高, 缝衣服, 重新阅读书籍*
*Then I'll stretch, maybe sketch.
Take a climb, sew a dress, and I'll re-read the books.*
*如果我有空闲时间, 我将把它画在
墙上一些,我敢肯定有空间的地方*
*If I have time to spare, I'll paint the wall
some more, I'm sure there's room somewhere.*
*然后我就梳, 梳, 梳, 梳我的头发*
*And then I'll brush, and brush, and brush,
and brush my hair.*
*我一直停留在同一个地方*
*Stuck in the same place
I've always been.*
*我会继续疑惑, 不知道..不知道...*
*And I'll keep wondering, and wondering,
and wondering...*
*何时我的人生将展开？*
*Wondering, when will my life begin?*
*明天晚上, 灯光将出现*
*Tomorrow night, the lights will appear.*
*就像他们每年帮我庆生*
*Just like they do on my birthday,
each year.*
*外面世界是什么样子, 在那些发光处？*
*What is it like, out there
where they glow?*
*既然, 我长大了 妈妈可能会让我走*
*Now that I'm older. Mother
might just let me go.*
哇！ 这样壮观的景致, 看多了, 我可要习惯了!
I could get used to a view like this.
-莱德, 来吧
-等一下
- Ryder, come on.
- Hold on.
是的, 我已经习惯了, 伙计们, 我想要有一座城堡
Yep, I'm used to it.
Guys I want a castle.
我们做完这一票, 你可以买自己的城堡
We do this job, you could
buy your own castle.
哦, 花粉症？
Oh, hay fever?
对
Yeah.
嗯…
Huh?
等等, 等等嘿, 等等！
Wait, wait.Hey, wait!
你能不能想像, 我已经有自己的城堡了？
我的意思是, 我当然可以
Can't you picture me in a castle of 'Cause I certainly can.
my own?
哦, 又在做白日梦了, 现在才早上八点
Oh, the things we've seen and
it's only eight in the morning.
先生们, 这是一个非常伟大的一天
Gentlemen, this is a very big day.
就是今天 这是一个非常重要的日子, 帕斯卡
This is it. This is
a very big day, Pascal.
我终于要做这一件事
I'm finally going to do it.
我要去问她 ........ 长发姑娘!
- I'm going to ask her. RAPUNZEL!
放下你的头发
Let down your hair.
时间到了
It's time.
我知道, 我知道 来吧, 不要让她看到你
I know, I know. Come on, don't
let her see you.
长发姑娘, 我可不年轻的啦
Rapunzel, I'm not getting any
younger down here.
来了, 母亲
Coming, mother.
您好, 欢迎回家, 母亲
Hi, welcome home, mother.
哦, 长发姑娘, 你怎么能每一次都做到,
Oh, Rapunzel. How you manage to do
that every single day,
不会失败, 看起来很累人耶, 亲爱的
without fail, it looks absolutely
exhausting, darling.
哦, 这没什么
Oh, it's nothing.
但是, 我怀疑为什么要这么久
Then I don't know why it
takes so long.
哦, 亲爱的, 我只是在开玩笑
Oh, darling. I'm just teasing.
好吧, 所以...
All right... so, mother.
As you know tomorrow is a very big day.
-妈妈你知道明天是一个重要的日子
-长发姑娘, 看着镜子, 你知道我看到了什么？
Rapunzel look in that mirror.
You know what I see?
我看到一个强大, 自信, 年轻漂亮的姑娘
I see a strong, confident,
beautiful young lady.
喔, 看, 你也在那里,
开玩笑的啦 !! 别那么认真好吗  ?
Oh look, you're here too. I'm just teasing, stop taking
everything so seriously.
好了, 妈妈, 正如我说的, 明天...
Okay, so mother. As I was saying, tomorrow...
花儿, 妈妈感觉没那么年轻了
Rapunzel, mother's feeling a little run down.
你会为我歌唱吧, 亲爱的？
Would you sing for me, dear?
然后再谈哦！-- 当然, 妈妈
- Then we'll talk.- OH! Of course, mother.
（歌唱得非常快）*花发亮和发光, 发光,
让你的力量, 使时光倒转, 带回曾经的我*
*Flower gleam and glow, Let your power shine,
Make the clock reverse, bring back what once was mine.*
*治愈所有伤害, 改变命运设计拯救已经丢失, 带回曾经的我*
*Heal what has been hurt, Change the fate's design.
Save what has been lost, Bring back what once was mine.*
长发姑娘！,
所以, 母亲,
- Rapunzel!
- So, mother,
刚才我问, 明天是否是一个重要的日子, 你还没回答,
Earlier I was saying that tomorrow was a
pretty big day, and you didn't really respond,
所以我要告诉你, 明天是我的生日！
So I'm just going to tell you.
It's my birthday!
答达！
TADA!
不, 不, 不, 不可能
No, no, no can't be.
我清楚地记得, 你的生日是去年
I distinctly remember. Your
birthday was last year.
生日是有趣的事, 它是一年一度的
That's the funny thing about birthdays.
They're kind of an annual thing.
母亲, 我要十八岁了
Mother, I'm turning eighteen.
而我想, 这个生日我真的想要的 .....
And I wanted to ask,
what I really want for this birthday.
其实我每一个生日都（喃喃自语）..
Actually what I want for
长发姑娘, 请停止喃喃自语
Rapunzel please, stop with the mumbling.
你知道我讨厌喃喃自语
You know how I feel about the mumbling.
布啦, 布啦, 布啦, 布啦...这是非常恼人的
Blah, blah, blah,... blah.
It's very annoying.
我只是开玩笑, 你很可爱, 亲爱的
I'm just teasing, you're adorable
I love you so much, darling.
哦, 我想去看天灯
Oh, I want to see the floating lights.
什么？噢,
- What? -Oh,...
嗯, 我希望你能带我去看那些天灯
Well I was hoping you would
take me to see the floating lights.
-欧.. 你是说那些星星吗 ?
-妈妈, 是这样的 !!
Oh, you mean the stars. That's the thing
我有星座图 星星总是不变的
I've charted stars and they're
always constant.
但这些, 他们每年都会出现在我的生日, 妈妈
But these, they appear every year
on my birthday, Mother.
只有在我的生日那天
Only on my birthday.
而我不禁觉得,
And I can't help but feel that they're,
他们是为我而来
They're meant for me.
我需要去看他们, 母亲, 而不只是从窗边看
I need see them, Mother.
And not just from my window.
亲自去
In person.
我必须知道它们是什么
I have to know what they are.
你要到外面去？
You want to go outside?
哦, 为什么, 长发姑娘
Oh, why Rapunzel.
看看你, 脆弱的像朵花
Look at you, as
fragile as a flower.
*仍然是一个小树苗, 才刚发芽*
*Still a little sapling, just a sprout.*
-*你知道为什么我们住在这塔里*
- 我知道, 但...
- *You know why we stay up in this tower*
- I know, but...
*那就对了, 为了你的安全, 健康, 亲爱的*
*Thats right, to keep you safe,
and sound, dear.*
*我一直都知道这一天快来了*
*Guess I always knew this day was coming.*
*知道没多久, 你就会想离开这里*
*Know that soon you'd want
to leave the nest.*
*很快, 但不是现在, 相信我，母亲最了解*
- *Soon, but not yet. Shhh..Trust me pet, Mother, knows best.*
*母亲最清楚,*
*Mother knows best,*
*听你妈的话*
*listen to your mother.*
*外面是一个可怕的世界*
*It's a scary world
out there.*
*母亲最清楚*
*Mother knows best.*
*无论什么事情, 都可能会出错, 我发誓*
*One way or another, something
will go wrong, I swear.*
*歹徒, 暴徒, 毒藤, 流沙*
*Ruffians, thugs, poison Ivy,
quicksand.*
*食人族, 蛇, 鼠疫*
*Cannibals, and snakes,
the plague... yes.*
*大虫, 有尖牙齿的男子*
*Also large bugs, men with pointy teeth.*
*所以停止, 别再说了, 你只是让我伤心*
*And stop, no more,
you'll just upset me.*
*妈妈就在这里, 妈妈会保护你*
*Mother's right here,
mother will protect you.*
*亲爱的 这就是我的建议*
*Darling here's what I suggest.*
*别再胡思, 留下陪妈*
*Skip the drama,
stay with Mama.*
*母亲, 最清楚*
*Mother, knows best.*
*母亲最清楚 别再乱想*
*Mother knows best.
Take it from your mumsey.*
*靠你自己, 你将无法生存*
*On your own, you won't survive.*
*邋遢不得体, 不成熟, 笨拙,*
*Sloppy underdressed, immature, clumsy,*
*请啊, 他们活活, 吃掉你*
*Please, they'll eat you up,
alive.*
*轻信, 天真, 肮脏*
*Gullible, naive,
positively grubby.*
*愚蠢, 还有一点, 嗯, 含糊*
*Ditzy and a bit,
well, hmm vague.*
*另外, 我相信, 会越来越胖*
*Plus I believe, getting
kinda chubby.*
*我这样说, 因为我爱你*
*I'm just saying,
'Cause I wuv you.*
*母亲明白, 母亲是来帮你*
*Mother understands,
Mothers here to help you.*
*我只有一个请求*
*All I have is one request.*
-长发姑娘？-是！
- Rapunzel?- Yes?
永远不要再要求离开此塔
Don't ever ask to
leave this tower, again.
是的, 妈妈
Yes, Mother.
啊, 我非常爱你, 亲爱的
Ahh, I love you very much, dear.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
我最爱你
I love you most.
不要忘记它
Don't forget it.
*你会后悔的*
*You'll regret it.*
*母亲..*
*Motherrrrrrr.*
*最清楚*
*Knows best.*
长发姑娘, 我会再来看你, 我的花儿
Ta, ta, I'll see you
in a bit, my flower.
我会在这里
I'll be here.
不, 不, 不, 这是非常, 非常糟糕, 这是非常糟糕的
No, no no. This is bad, this is
very, very bad, This is really bad.
我的鼻子 怎么是这样呢 ?
They just can't get my nose right.
没有人会在意的
Who cares.
对你来说很容易
Well it's easy for you to say.
你们看起来好棒!
You guys look amazing.
好吧, 好吧, 帮我抬上去, 我再拉你们上来.
All right, okay. Give me a boost,
and I'll pull you up.
先把背包给我们
Give us the satchel first.
啥 ..？我只是...
Wha..? I just...
我无法相信, 毕竟我们是一伙的,
I can't believe, that after all
we've been through together,
你不信任我
you don't trust me.
哎呀
Ouch.
现在帮助我们, 漂亮男孩
Now help us up, pretty boy.
对不起, 我的手没空
Sorry, my hands are full.
怎么？
What?
莱德！
RYDER!
全力夺回那个背包. 是的, 长官
- Retrieve that satchel with any force.
- Yes, sir!
我们要逮到他了, 马克西姆斯
We got him now, Maximus.
加油！
Heeyah!
来吧！ 畜生, 前进
Heeyah! Come flea-bag, forward.
真的不行
No.
不, 住手 别...这样！
No, stop it. Stop it.
把它给我
Give it to me.
哈！ -啊...！- (马)啊！
WHINNEYY!
喔！ 终于只剩我一人
Alone at last.
好吧, 好吧, 好吧,有一个人在我的衣柜里
Okay, okay, I got a person in my closet.
有一个人 在我的衣柜里
I got a person in my closet.
有一个人在我的衣柜里 !!!
I've got a person in my closet!
妈妈还说我太弱小, 无法在外独立, 哈 !
To weak to handle myself
out there, huh Mother?
嗯, 来跟我的锅子说... 吧
Well, Tell that to my frying pan.
长发姑娘！
Rapunzel!
放下你的头发
Let down your hair.
马上来, 妈妈
One moment, Mother.
我有一个很大的惊喜
I have a big surprise.
嗯, 我也有
Uh, I do too.
哦, 我敢打赌, 我的是更大的惊喜
Oh, I bet my surprise is bigger.
我不这样认为
I seriously doubt it.
我找到防风草了 我准备做榛子果仁汤当晚饭, 你的最爱
I brought back parsnips. I'm going to make
hazel nut soup for dinner, your favorite.
惊喜吧！
Surprise!
好, 妈妈, 有件事情我想告诉你
Well mother, there's something
I want to tell you.
哦, 长发姑娘, 你知道我讨厌 吵架后就走开
Oh Rapunzel, you know I hate
leaving you after a fight.
尤其是我没有做错的时候
Especially when I've done
absolutely nothing wrong.
好吧, 我已经想了很多关于你早先说的话
Okay, I've been thinking a lot
about what you said, earlier.
我不希望你还要谈星星
I hope you're not still talking
about the stars.
天灯, 这就是我要说的问题
Floating lights, and yes
I'm leading up to that.
我以为我们放弃了那个话题了, 亲爱的
Because I really thought
we dropped the issue, sweetheart.
不, 母亲, 我只是说,
No Mother, I'm just saying,
你觉得, 我没有足够的力量在外照顾自己
you think I'm not strong enough
to handle myself out there.
亲爱的, 我知道你没有足够的力量在外面照顾自己
Oh darling, I know you're not strong
enough to handle yourself out there.
-但是你只要...,
-长发姑娘, 我们别再谈论这个问题
- But if you just...
- Rapunzel, we're done talking about this.
-相信我, 我..-长发姑娘
- Trust me,...- Rapunzel.
-我...知道
-长发姑娘
- ...I know what I'm
- Rapunzel.
-哦, 好吧,
-这就是你的人生, 长发姑娘
- Oh, come on.
- Enough with the lights, Rapunzel.
你不会离开这座塔, 永远不会！
You are not leaving this tower,EVER!
哦, 太棒了 !!
现在 我变成了个坏蛋
Oh, great. Now I'm the bad guy.
我只想说, 妈妈, 那个...
All I was gonna say, mother ,is that...
现在我知道我的生日要什么了
I know what I want for my birthday, now.
喔, 是什么？
And what is that?
新的油漆, 你曾经给我过的
白色贝壳制成的油漆
New paint. That paint made from
the white shells you once brought me.
啊 那要走很远耶, 长发姑娘
Well that is a very long trip,Rapunzel.
几乎要三天的时间
Almost three day's time.
我只是觉得这是一个比星星, 更好的主意
I just thought it was a
better idea than, uh, stars.
你确定你会没事, 剩你一个人？
You sure you'll be all right,
on your own?
我知道我很安全, 只要待在这里
I know I'm safe, as long as I'm here.
我会在3天后回来
I'll be back in three days time.
我爱你, 亲爱的
I love you very much, dear.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
我最爱你
I love you most.
好了
Okay.
什么？ 这是...头发？
Is this... hair?
挣扎 ...挣扎是没有意义的
Struggling... struggling is pointless.
我知道你为什么来这里
I know why you're here.
而且我不怕你
And I'm not afraid of you.
什么？
What?
你是谁, 你是怎么找到我的？
Who are you, and how
did you find me?
你是谁, 你是怎么找到我的？
I know not who you are.
我不知道你是谁, 我也不是来找你
Nor how I came to find you.
不过, 我只想说
But may I just say.
嗨
Hi!
你好吗？
How you doing?
我的名字是 "弗林莱德"
The name's Flynn Ryder.
过得怎样呀, 啊？
How's your day going, huh?
还有谁知道我住的地方, 弗林莱德？
Who else knows my location,
Flynn Ryder?
-好吧, 金发女郎-我是长发姑娘
- All right, Blondie.- Rapunzel.
幸会!! , 事实是...
Gesundheit, here's the deal.
我因为某种情况, 闲逛穿过森林
I was in a situation,
Gallivanting through the forest.
恰巧发现你的塔, 和...
I came across your tower and...
哈, 哦, 不, 我的背包在哪里？
Ho, oh no, where is my satchel?
我藏在了某个地方, 你永远也找不到它
I've hidden it, somewhere you'll
never find it.
它在那锅里, 是不是
It's in that pot, isn't it.
啊, 别舔我耳朵啦 !
Ahh, will you stop that.
现在, 它藏好了, 你永远也找不到它
Now it's hidden where you'll never find it.
所以, 你到底想拿我的头发去干嘛？
So, what do you want,with my hair?
-要剪它？-什么？
- To cut it?- What?
-卖掉它？-不,
- Sell it?- No!
听着, 我唯一想对你的头发做的事,
Listen, the only thing I want
to do with your hair,
就是要摆脱它, 完完全全的摆脱它
is to get out of it.Literally.
等等, 你不想要我的头发？
Wait, you don't want my hair?
我为什么 会想要你的头发？
Why on earth would I want your hair?
听着, 我被追赶, 我看到了一座塔,
我爬上来, 就是这样 .....
Look, I was being chased, I saw a
tower, I climbed it, end of story.
你是, 说真话？
You're, telling the truth?
是的!
Yes.
我知道, 但是他可以带我去 .....
I know, maybe he's the one
to take me.
我认为他说的是实话
I think he's telling the truth, too.
他应该没恶意的, 而且, 我还有什么选择？
Nothing I think,
but what choice do I have?
嗯, 好吧
弗林莱德, 我们来谈个交易
Uh, okay Flynn Ryder,
I'm prepared to offer you a deal.
交易？ 看这边
- Deal?- Look this way.
你知道这是什么？
Do you know what these are?
你是指他们为公主做的灯笼？
You mean the lantern thing
they do for the princess?
灯笼 ...
Lanterns...
我就知道他们不是星星
I knew they weren't stars.
那么, 明天晚上他们将照亮夜空,
Well, tomorrow evening
they will light the night sky,
用这些灯笼, 您将作为我的导游,
with these lanterns.
You will act as my guide,
带我去看这些灯笼, 再带我平安回家
Take me to these lanterns,
and return me home safely.
那时, 也只有到那时, 我会把你的背包还你
Then, and only then, will
I return your satchel to you.
这是我的条件
That is my deal.
是啊, 不可能
Yeah, no can do.
不幸的是, 在此刻, 王国和我相处的, 不太好,
Unfortunately, the kingdom and I
aren't exactly, simpatico,
所以, 我不会带你到任何地方
at the moment. So I
won't be taking you anywhere.
什么风把你吹来的, 弗林莱德
Something brought you here,Flynn Ryder.
-可能是你的意志, 命运, 天意 ....
-是一匹马带我来的啦
- Call it what you will, fate, destiny.
- A horse.
所以, 我已经决定信任你
So I have made the decision to
trust you.
一个可怕的决定, 真的
A horrible decision, really.
但是请相信我, 当我告诉你这一点
But trust me, when I tell you this.
你可以拆开此塔, 一砖一瓦的
You can tear this tower apart,
brick by brick.
但没有我的帮助, 你永远都不会找到你的宝贵背包
But without my help, you will
never find your precious satchel.
让我们把话说清楚
Let me just get this straight.
我带你去看天灯
I take you to see the lanterns.
然后再带你回来
Bring you back home,
你就把背包还给我？
and you'll give me back my satchel?
我保证
I promise.
而且我答应过的事, 我向来都会做到
And when I promise something, I never
ever break that promise.
永远都会！
EVER!
好吧, 听着, 我本来不希望这么做,
All right, listen, I didn't want
to have to want to do this,
但你让我 别无选择
but you leave me no choice.
看我  帅哥的 '电眼媚功'
Here comes the 'smolder'.
看来我这功夫 不管用了
This is kind of an off day for me.
这通常不会发生
This doesn't normally happen.
好吧, 我带你去看天灯
Fine, I'll take you to see the lanterns.
真的吗？
Really!
哎呀, 我的 '电眼媚功' 被你毁了 !!!
- Ooops.- You broke my 'smolder'.
快下来, 金发女郎？
You coming, Blondie?
*看世界如此接近, 离我只剩半步了*
*Look at the world so close, and I'm
half way to it*
*看看这辽阔一切, 我真的敢吗？*
*Look at it all, so big
do I even dare?*
*看看我, 终于, 我做到了*
*Look at me, here at last
I just have to do it.*
我应做吗？不
Should I? No.
我来了
Here I go.
*我闻到草和泥土的芳香就像我梦中的*
*Triumphant music*
*感受那夏日的微风*
*Just smell the grass, the dirt.
Just like I dreamed they'd be.*
*她正呼唤着我*
*Just feel that summer breeze.*
*就像是第一次, 我是完完全全自由的*
*The way it's calling me.*
*我可以跑步, 赛跑, 跳舞...*
*For like the first time ever,
I'm completely free.*
*和追逐, 蹦着, 跳着*
*I could go running, and racing,
and dancing...
*头发飞扬, 心砰砰的跳,*
*and chasing, and leaping
and bounding.*
*我终于明白,*
*hair flying, heart pounding
and splashing and reeling.*
*现在我的人生开展了*
*And finally feeling,*
我简直不敢相信我这样做
*Now's when my life
begins.*
（喃喃自语中）我真不敢相信 我这样做,
我不相信我会这么做！
I can't believe I did this. I can't believe I did this.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I DID THIS!
妈妈会非常气愤
Mother would be so furious.
这没关系, 不知道的事, 不会杀了她, 对不对？
That's okay, what she doesn't
know won't kill her, right?
噢, 我的天哪, 这会杀了她
Oh my gosh, this would kill her.
这太好玩了！
THIS IS SO FUN!
我是一个糟糕的女儿, 我要回去
I am a horrible daughter,
I'm going back.
我将永远不回去去去去去去！
I am never going
baaaccckkk!
我是一个卑鄙的人
I am a despicable human being.
最好的一天, 永远！
Best day, ever!
你知道, 我不禁的注意到,
You know, I can't help but notice,
-你似乎有点 ... 在跟自己对抗
-
you seem a little at war
with yourself, here.
你说什么 ???
你整天都是这样 , 隐隐约约我感觉到
- What?
- Now, I'm only picking up bits and pieces,
似乎是被母亲保护过度, 你偷偷溜出来一样 ...
of course, over protective mother,forbidden road trip.
我的意思是, 这是严肃的事情
I mean, this is serious stuff.
不过, 让我减轻 你的罪恶感, 这就是成长的一部分
But let me ease your conscious. This is part of growing up.
有点反叛, 有点冒险
这是很好的, 甚至是很健康的
A little rebellion, a little adventure. That's good, healthy even.
你这样觉得？
You think?
我知道, 你想太多了啦 !!
I know. You're way over thinking this, trust me.
难道你母亲是活该嘛？ 当然不
Did your mother deserve it?No.
这是否会让她心碎, 冲撞她的灵魂？
Will this break her heart
and crush her soul?
嗯, 当然会. 但是, 你本来就应该做的啊!
Of course.
But you just got to do it.
让她心碎？
Break her heart?
-对, 碎成两半 ..
-冲撞她的灵魂？
- In half.
- Crush her soul?
像颗葡萄
Like a grape.
她会心碎的, 你说得对
She would be heart broken,
you're right.
当然对啦 !! 唉.. 我替你难过 .....
I am, oh my, oh bother.
好吧, 我不能相信我这样说, 但是...
All right, I can't believe I'm
saying this, but...
我愿意让你 中止这笔交易
I'm letting you out of the deal.
-什么？-没错
- What?- That's right.
别谢我, 让我们现在转身,
But don't thank me. Let's
just turn around,
我送你回家, 还有你的青蛙
and get you home, and your frog.
我拿回我的背包,
I get back my satchel.
你也能维持 良好的母女关系
You get back a mother
daughter relationship
基于相互信任 和什么的！
based on mutual trust and viola!
我们就像无缘的朋友, 分道扬镳
We part ways as unlikely friends.
-不, 我要去看灯笼,
-哦, 拜托！
- No, I am seeing those lanterns.
- Oh, come on!
到底要我怎样, 你才会还我背包？
What is it going to take
to get my satchel back?
我会用这个喔
I will use this.
它是什么, 地痞, 流氓？来找我的？
Is it, ruffians, thugs?
Have they come for me?
保持冷静, 它也许以为你怕它
Stay calm, it can probably smell fear.
噢, 对不起
Oh, sorry.
我只是有一点点, 紧张 ....
Guess I'm a little bit, jumpy.
但小心为上, 如果我们要面对暴徒和恶棍的话
Probably be best if we avoid
ruffians and thugs, though.
是啊, 小心为上
Yeah, that probably be best.
你饿吗？我知道一个吃午饭的好地方
Are you hungry?
I know a great place for lunch.
哪儿？, 哦, 不要担心
- Where?- Oh, don't you worry.
当你闻到它你就知道
You'll know it when you smell it.
哦, 一匹官马
Oh, a Palace horse.
你的主人在哪里？
Where's your rider?
长发姑娘
Rapunzel.
长发姑娘！
RAPUNZEL!
长发姑娘, 放下你的头发
Rapunzel, let down your hair.
长发姑娘？
Rapunzel?
Rapunzel!
长发姑娘！
RAPUNZEL!
我知道是在这里的某个地方
I know it's around here, somewhere.
啊, 就在这里
Ah, there it is.
舒服的小鸭
The Snuggly duckling.
别担心, 很古朴的地方, 很适合你
Don't worry, very quaint place,
perfect for you.
不会让你吓跑, 并放弃我们一切努力, 会吗？
Don't want you scaring, and giving
up on this whole endeavor now do we?
恩, 我喜欢小鸭, 耶！
- Well, I do like duckling.- YAY!
服务生, 请给我你最好的位置
Garcon, your finest table, please.
你闻到了吗？深吸一口气通过鼻子
You smell that?
Take a deep breath through the nose.
真的, 是非常糟糕
Really let that seep in.
你闻到些什么？因为对我来说, 它有点不太好闻
What are you getting?
Because to me, it's part man smell.
甚至是令人很不舒服的味道
And the other part is
really bad man smell.
我不知道为什么, 但总体而言, 它的气味令人毛骨悚然
I don't know why, but overall,
it just smells like the color brown.
你的想法？
Your thoughts?
这真的是很多的头发
That's a lot of hair.
她生来长发, 你的胡子上是血吗？
She's growing it out, is that blood
on your moustache?
戈尔迪, 看看这个, 看他的胡子上有血
Goldie, look at this, look at
all the blood on his moustache.
你看, 我敢肯定, 流了很多血
Look sir, that's a lot of blood.
嘿, 你看起来不太好, 金发女郎
Hey, you don't look so good, Blondie.
也许我们应该让你回家, 收工啦
Maybe we should get you home.
Call it a day.
会比这一个五星级的酒店更好过
Probably be better off. This is a five
star joint after all.
如果你不能应付这个地方, 那也许你应该回到你的塔
And if you can't handle this place, well
maybe you should be back in your tower.
这是你吗？
Is this you?
不, 他的鼻子较丑
No, no this is being mean.
哦, 没错是他
Oh, it's him all right.
格雷塔, 去找警卫
Gretel, go find some guards.
那奖金可让我 换个新钩子
That reward's going to
buy me a new hook.
我也要这笔钱
I can use the money.
那我呢？我身无分文
What about me?
I'm broke.
大伙, 住手！, 我们想办法解决
- Boys, stop!
- We can work this out.
嘿, 放开他
Hey, leave him alone.
先生们, 请, 把我的向导还我
- Gentlemen, please.
- Give me back my guide, ruffians.
别打鼻子, 别打鼻子, 别打鼻子！
Not the nose, not the nose,
not the nose!
把他放下来！
Put him down!
好吧, 我不知道这是哪里, 但我需要他带我去看天灯,
Okay, I don't know where I am,
and I need him to take me to see the lanterns,
因为我这是我一生的梦想
because I've been dreaming about
them my entire life.
你们有点人性吧!
Find your humanity.
难道你们没有任何梦想？
Havent any of you ever had a dream?
我, 有个梦想
I, had a dream.
曾经有过 .....
Once.
*我充满恶意而且可怕*
*I'm malicious mean and scary.*
*我的冷笑可以凝固牛奶*
*My sneer could curdle dairy.*
*我暴力的手也不是顶干净*
*And violence-wise my hands
are not the cleanest.*
*但是, 尽管我有恶毒的眼神, 我的脾气和我的钩子*
*But despite my evil look,
and my temper and my hook.*
*我一直渴望成为一个音乐会钢琴家*
*I've always yearned to
be a concert pianist.*
*难道你没看见我在舞台上表演莫扎特*
*Can't cha see me on the stage
performing Mozart.*
*搔痒着琴键, 直到他们发出光芒*
*Tickling the ivories,
'til they gleam.*
*是的, 我宁愿被称为致命*
*Yep, I'd rather be called deadly.*
*但那是指我有杀手般的乐曲表演...谢谢*
*For my killer show-tune medley.
Thank you.*
*因为在我内心深处我有一个梦想*
*'Cause way down deep inside
I've got a dream.*
*他有一个梦想, 他有一个梦想*
*He's got a dream,
he's got a dream.*
*明白吗, 我不是我看起来那样残忍恶毒的*
*See, I ain't as cruel and
vicious as I seem.*
*虽然你以为我会打断你的骨头*
*Though I feel like breaking femurs.*
*你可以指望我是个梦想家*
*You can count me with the dreamers.*
*和其他人一样, 我有梦想*
*Like everybody else,
I've gotta dream.*
*我有伤痕和肿块和瘀伤*
*I've got scars and lumps and bruises.*
*这里还有怪东西在渗出*
*Plus something here that oozes.*
*而且, 我们甚至没有提及我的肤色*
*Let's not even mention
my complexion.*
*忘掉我多出的脚趾*
*But despite my extra toes.*
*我的甲状腺肿大, 我的鼻子*
*And my goiter and my nose.*
*我真的想谈个恋爱*
*I really want to make a love
connection.*
*你没看见我和一个特殊的小女人*
*Can't you see me with a special
little lady.*
*沿着溪流, 划着小船*
*Rowing in a row boat,
down the stream.*
*虽然我是一个恶心的家伙*
*Though I'm one disgusting blighter.*
*我是一个情人, 而不是一个战士*
*I'm a lover, not a fighter.*
*因为在我的内心深处, 我有梦想*
*'Cause way down deep
inside, I gotta dream.*
*我有梦想, 我有梦想*
*I gotta dream,
I gotta dream.*
*我知道我永远不可能位居高位*
*And I know one day
will never reign supreme.*
*虽然我的脸使人们尖叫*
*Though my face leaves
people screaming.*
*但背后有一个孩子的梦想*
*There's a child behind
it dreaming.*
*和其他人一样, 我有梦想*
*Like everybody else,
I've gotta dream.*
*多尔 想洗手改行, 开一个花店*
*冈瑟 想做室内设计*
*Tor would like to quit Gunther does interior design and be a florist.*
*乌尔夫 演默剧,
阿提拉 的蛋糕超棒*
*Ulf is into mime,Attila cupcakes are sublime.*
*布鲁瑟 针织, 凯勒 缝纫 方邓 喜欢做小木偶秀*
*Bruiser knits, Killer sews. Fang does little puppet shows.*
*而 弗拉基 收集陶瓷独角兽*
*And Vladimir collects ceramic unicorns.*
那你呢？
What about you?
对不起 我吗？
你有什么梦想？
- I'm sorry, me?
- What's your dream?
不, 不, 不 对不起 大伙, 我不会唱歌
No, no, no. Sorry boys,
I don't sing.
*我跟你们一样有梦, 但有一点不同*
*I have dreams like you,no really.*
*只是没有那么 露骨肉麻*
*Just much less, touchy-feely.*
*我梦想着某处 温暖和阳光充足之处*
*They mainly happen somewhere
warm and sunny.*
*在一个属于自己的小岛上, 晒黑, 休息, 自在*
*On an island that I own,
tanned and rested and alone.*
*周围有 成堆成堆的钱*
*Surrounded by enormous
piles of money.*
* 我有一个梦 ...  我有一个梦想*
*（暴徒们）, 她有一个梦想*
*-I've got a dream... I've got a dream.
- She got a dream.*
*我只是想看看 天灯升空发光*
*I just want to see the floating
lanterns gleam.*
*而每过一个小时 我就越高兴 能离开了我的塔*
*And with every passing hour.I'm so glad I left my tower.*
*像你们这些可爱的人, 我有一个梦想*
*Like all you lovely folks,I've got a dream.*
*她有梦想, 他也有梦想 他们都有梦想, 我们都有梦想*
*She's gotta dream, He's gotta dream.
They've gotta dream, we've gotta dream.*
*因此, 我们的分歧也不大, 我们是一个大的团队*
*So our differences ain't really that extreme.
We're one big team.*
*可以说我们是残暴, 野蛮, 荒唐的乐观
*Call us brutal, say sadistic
and grotesquely optimistic.
*因为在我们内心深处, 我们拥有梦想*
*'Cause way down deep inside,
we've gotta dream.*
*我们有梦想, 我有梦想*
*We gotta dream,
I gotta dream.*
*是的 在这里每个人都有着...*
*Yes way down deep inside
we've got a...*
* 梦想... ... ..*
*Dreeeeeeaaaaamm.*
耶 ! 我找到警卫了
I found the guards.
莱德在哪里, 他在哪儿？
Where's Ryder,where is he?
我知道他在这里的某个地方
I know he's in here somewhere.
找到他, 整个地方翻过来！
Find him, turn the place upside down if you have to!
去, 实现你的梦想
Go, live your dream.
我会的
I will.
你的梦想烂透了, 我是说她的
Your dream stinks,
I was talking to her.
谢谢你们的帮助
Thanks for everything.
我相信这是你要找的人
I believe this is the man
you're looking for.
你抓到我了
You got me.
长官, 没有任何莱德的迹象
Sir, there's no sign of Ryder.
马克西姆斯
Maximus.
它在做什么？
What's he doing?
一个密道, 来吧弟兄们, 走吧
A passage, come on men,
let's go.
科曼, 别让这些人逃脱了
Corman, make sure those
boys don't get away.
小心使用啊
Play it safe.
我们去抢王冠
We'll go get the crown.
我有梦想, 我有一些梦想
I gotta dream,
I got some dream.
你好, 哦, 我是喝多了
I..., ohhh, somebody get me a glass.
因为我看到一个高大的美女
Because I just found me a
tall drink of water.
哦, 得了吧, 大耳朵
Oh stop it, you big lug.
那条密道通往哪里？
Where does that tunnel lead out?
刀子！
Knife!
嗯, 我得说
Well, that got us safe.
你刚刚的表现 ... 让人印象深刻 ...
Didn't know you had that in you
back there. That was pretty, impressive.
我知道！
I KNOW!
我懂!
I know...
那么.. 弗林, 你是哪里人？
Sooo, Flynn. Where are you from?
哇, 哇, 对不起 金发女郎, 我不喜欢说故事
Whoa, whoa, sorry Blondie,
I don't do back story.
不过, 我却对你的故事 很感兴趣
However I am becoming very
interested in yours.
我知道.. 我不应该提你的 "头发"
Now I... I know I'm not suppose
to mention the hair.
-当然不,
-或者提到 "母亲"
- Nope.
- Or, the Mother.
-嗯, 嗯,
-坦白说, 我也怕问你那只 "青蛙" 的事
Frankly I'm to scared to
ask about the frog.
-是变色龙啦 ..
-差别不大
- Chameleon.
- Nuance.
我的问题是, 如果你这么想去看天灯,
Here's my question though, if you want
to see the lanterns so badly,
你为什么从前不去？
why haven't you gone before?
嗯, 弗林...
Uh, Flynn...
弗林！
Flynn!
快跑！
Run, RUN!
他们是谁？
Who's that?
他们不喜欢我
They don't like me.
-那他们是谁？,
-他们也不喜欢我
- Who's that?
- They don't like me either.
-那又是谁？
-就让我们假定此时...
- Who's that?
- Lets just assume for the moment,
这里的每个人 都不喜欢我
that everyone here doesn't like me.
拿着
Here.
我等这一刻 已经等了很久
I've waited a long time for this.
哦, 妈妈, 我得买个一摸一样的
Oh mama, I have got to get me
one of these.
你应该知道, 这是我做过最奇怪的事
You should know that this is
the strangest thing I've ever done.
三战两胜怎么样？
How 'bout two out of three?
弗林, 当心点
Flynn, look out.
哇, 呜哇！
Hold on.
你应该看看你的脸, 因为你看起来...
You should see your faces.
Because you look...
很可笑！
Ridiculous
来吧, 金发女郎
Come on, Blondie.
跳
Jump.
这样没有用的, 我什么也看不见
It's no use,
I can't see anything.
嘿, 那样毫无意义
Hey, there's no point.
那里是一片漆黑
It's pitch black down there.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
她是对的, 我不应该这样做
She was right, I never
should have done this.
我很...
I'm so...
我很抱歉, 弗林
I'm so sorry, Flynn.
尤金
Eugene.
什么？
What?
我真正的名字是, 尤金 菲茨赫伯特
( Eugene Fitzherbert )
My real name is,
Eugene Fitzherbert.
所以, 不妨让你知道吧 ..
So you might as well know.
我有神奇的头发, 唱歌时, 它就会闪亮
I have magic hair that glows
when I sing.
什么？
What?
我有神奇的头发, 唱歌时, 它就会闪亮
I have magic hair,
that glows when I sing.
*花儿闪亮而发光让你的力量闪耀*
*Flower gleam and glow.
Let your power shine.*
我们成功了
We made it.
她的头发 会发光 !!
Her hair glows.
我还活着, 我还活着！
I'm alive.
I'm alive!
怎么会有这种事 ? 她的头发真的会发光
I didn't see that coming.
Her hair actually glows.
-尤金...,
-她的头发为什么会发光？
- Eugene...
- Why does her hair glow?
-尤金！-什么？
- Eugene!- What?
它不仅仅会发光而已 ...
It doesn't just glow.
它为什么 对着我笑？
Why is he smiling at me?
我会杀了他
I'll kill him.
我要杀了, 莱德
I'll kill that, Ryder.
我们要阻止他去王国
We'll head him off at the kingdom.
要取回王冠, 来吧
And get back the crown, come on.
孩子们
Boys.
也许你要停止像个野狗 追逐自己的尾巴,
Perhaps you want to stop acting
like wild dogs chasing their tails,
好好的想一想
and think for a moment.
哦, 拜托没有必要那样
Oh, please there's no
need for that.
那么, 如果这就是你想要的, 拿去吧
Well if that's all you desire,
then be on your way.
我还想向你提供一件.. 价值千顶王冠的事,
I was going to offer you something
worth one thousand crowns,
将会使你富有的难以置信
would have made you
rich beyond belief.
这甚至不是最好的部分
And that wasn't even the best part.
哦, 这就是人生
Oh well, C'est la vie.
好好享受你的王冠吧
Enjoy your crown.
那什么是 最好的一部分？
What's the best part?
它还能顺便报复 弗林莱德
It comes with revenge
on Flynn Ryder.
所以你在用你那奇怪神秘的魔法头发 包?我受伤的手?
So you're being strangely cryptic as you wrap
your magic hair around my injured hand.
-啊..抱歉
Sorry.
只是不要... 不要吓到喔
Just don't....
*花儿闪亮和发光
*Flower gleam and glow*
*让你的力量闪耀*
*Let your powers shine*
*使时光倒转*
*Make the clock reverse*
*带回曾经的我*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
*治愈了所有伤害*
*Heal what has been hurt.*
*改变命运的设计*
*Change the fates design.*
*拯救已经丢失的*
*Save what has been lost.*
*带回曾经的我*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
*曾经的我*
*What once was mine.*
-啊.....
-不要吓到喔
- Ah...
- Please don't freak out.
唉唉, 我没有吓到, 你吓到了吗？
Ahhh. I'm not freaking out,
are you freaking out?
不, 我只是对你的头发 和它的神奇魔力 很感兴趣,
No, I'm just very interested in your hair.
And the magical qualities that it possesses.
它... 这样已经有多久了？
How long has it been
doing that, exactly?
一直都是这样的, 我想..
Forever, I guess.
母亲说, 当我还是个婴儿时 有人试图把它剪下
Mother said when I was a baby
people tried to cut it.
他们希望把它占为己有
They wanted to take it for themselves.
但是, 一旦它被剪下
But, once it's cut.
它变成褐色, 并失去它的魔力
It turns brown, and looses its power.
这样的一个礼物, 它必须得到保护
A gift like that, it has to be protected.
这就是为什么 妈妈从来不让我...
That's why Mother never let me...
这就是为什么我.. 我从来没有离开过 ...
That's why... I never left the...
你从来没有离开过那座塔
You never left that tower.
而你还是会回去吗？
And you're still gonna go back?
不 ..是的
No... yes.
这很复杂的
It's complicated.
因此, 尤金 菲茨赫伯特, 是吧？
So, Eugene Fitzherbert, huh?
啊, 是啊, 咱们跳过悲惨的部分吧 ..
Ah yeah, well. I'll spare
you the sob story of
尤金 是个可怜的孤儿, 这有一点点啊...
poor orphan Eugene Fitzherbert, it's
a little bit of a...
这有一点点 令人沮丧
It's a little bit of a downer.
曾有一本书
There was this book.
有一本我每天晚上用来 读给弟弟妹妹们听的书
A book I used to read every
night to all the younger kids.
芬尼根莱德的故事, 虚张声势的无赖, 最富有的人..
The tales of Flynnigan Ryder. Swashbuckling rogue,
richest man alive.
跟女人关系不坏 , 没什么可炫耀的, 当然
Not bad with the ladies either. Nothing
to ever brag about, of course.
他也是个小偷吗？
Was he a thief too?
啊, 哦, 不是
Ahh, well no.
其实, 他有足够的钱, 来做任何他想做的事
Actually, he had enough
money to do anything that he wanted to do.
他可以去任何他想去的地方
He could go anywhere that
he wanted to go.
而且, 对一个 一无所有的孩子来说
And... and, for a kid,
with nothing.
我不知道, 我..
I don't know, I...
这似乎是一个 很好的化名
It just seemed like a better option.
你不能告诉任何人这件事 , 好吗？
You can't tell anyone,
about this, okay?
这可能毁了我的声誉
It could ruin my whole reputation.
啊, 我们不希望这样
Ahh, you wouldn't want that.
哦, 夸张的名声, 是男人的一切啊 !!
Oh, the thing about a reputation,
it's all that a man has.
嗯, 嗯... 我应该 .....
Um, well I should uh...
我, 我应该去找一些柴火
I, I should get some
more firewood.
嘿
Hey.
说真的, 我比较喜欢 "尤金菲茨赫伯特",
而不是 "弗林莱德"
For the record, I like Eugene Fitzherbert
much better than, Flynn Ryder.
那么, 你会是第一个
Well, then you'd be the first.
无论如何, 感谢你
But, thank you.
嗯, 我还以为他会一直待在这
Well, I thought he'd never leave.
妈妈？
Mother?
你好, 亲爱的
Hello, dear.
但是, 我..我.., 正想...
But I... I..., don't we...
你是怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
哦, 这真的很容易
Oh, it was easy really.
我只是听着 背叛的声音, 跟着来了..
I just listened for the sound of
complete and utter betrayal,
and followed that.
-母亲 ..., -我们回家, 长发姑娘
- Mother...- We're going home, Rapunzel.
-马上-你...你不明白
- Now.- You... You don't understand.
我踏上了最不可思议的旅程
I've been on this incredible journey.
我也看到和学到了很多东西
And I've seen and learned so much.
我甚至遇到一个人
I even met someone.
是的, 被通缉的小偷, 还真自豪啊
Yes, the wanted thief.
I'm so proud.
-来吧, 长发姑娘
-母亲, 等等...
- Come on, Rapunzel.
- Mother, wait.
我觉得...
I think
我觉得他喜欢我
I think he likes me.
喜欢你？拜托, 你痴呆啦
Likes you? Please, Rapunzel,
that's demented.
-但是母亲, 我..,
-这就是为什么 你不应该离开
- But mother, I...
- This is why you never should have left.
亲爱的, 这整个浪漫, 都是你的想像,
Dear this whole romance that
you've invented,
只是证明你不懂世事
just proves you're to naive to be here.
他为什么会喜欢你吗？别闹了, 真的
Why would he like you?
Oh come on now, really.
看看你, 你认为他会对你有好的印象吗 ?
Look at you, you think
that he's impressed?
做个乖孩子, 跟妈妈走
Don't be a dummy, come with mommy.
*母亲 ..*
*Mother...*
-不-不?
- NO!- No?
噢... 我想我懂了
I see how it is.
*长发姑娘, 最清楚*
*Rapunzel, knows best.*
*她现在那么成熟了*
*Rapunzel's so mature, now.*
*如此的聪明的大人了, 小姐*
*Such a clever grown up, miss.*
*长发姑娘最清楚*
*Rapunzel knows best.*
*好, 如果你现在这么肯定*
*Fine, if you're so sure now.*
*走向前去, 然后给他..这个！*
*Go ahead then give him, THIS!*
你怎么能?
How did you?
*这是他为什么在这里*
*This is why he's here.*
*不要让他欺骗了你*
*Don't let him deceive you.*
-*给他看, 你会了解的*
--我会的
*Give it to him, watch, you'll see.*
- I will.
*相信我 亲爱的, 他会很快离开你*
*Trust me my dear, that's
how fast he'll leave you.*
*我不会说我早告诉过你, ...不*
*I won't say I told you so... no.*
*长发姑娘最清楚*
*Rapunzel knows best.*
*所以, 如果他是一艘梦之船*
*So if he's such a dream boat.*
-*拿去, 测试他*
-母亲, 等等
*Go and put him, to the test.*
- Mother, wait.
*如果他真的说谎, 别来哭*
*If he's lying, don't come
crying.*
*母亲, 最清楚*
*Mother, knows best.*
所以, 嘿啊, 我能问你吗？
So, hey uh, can I ask you something?
是否有可能, 我的手会得到超强的能力？
Is there any chance that I'm going
to get super strength in my hand?
我不骗你, 如果真是这样, 那就了不得了 !!
Because I'm not going to lie.
That would be stupendous.
嘿, 你没事吧？
Hey, you all right?
哦, 对不起, 没事
Oh, sorry, yes.
只是嗯, 陷入了沉思, 我想
Just um, lost in thought,
I guess.
我的意思是.. 因为, 你看
I mean because here's the thing.
超人的帅劲, 我天生就有了
Superhuman good looks,
I've always had 'em.
但如果再加上 超人的力量？
Born with it, but superhuman strength?
想像一下那可能发生, 我只是...
Can you imagine the possibilities, I'm just...
要有点耐心, 男孩们, 好东西都需要等待 !
Patience boys. All good things
to those who wait.
嗯, 什么？
Hmm, what?
嗯, 我希望你是来道歉的
Well I hope you're
here to apologize.
啊！ 不, 不 放下我 住手！ ... ...放下我！
No, no put me down.Stop it. Let... me... go!
把他...还给我！
Give me, him.
哇！
Whoa,
哇, 哇, 哇, 哇
whoa, whoa, whoa.
别紧张, 男孩, 别紧张, 平静下来
Easy boy, easy,
calm down.
别紧张 小男孩...别紧张
Easy boy. Easy.
就是这样
That's it.
现在..  坐下
Now sit.
-坐... -啥 ??
- Sit.- What?
好, 放下靴子
Now drop the boot.
放下它
Drop it.
哦, 你真是个好孩子
Oh, you are such a good boy.
是的, 你是
Yes you are.
你很累了吧, 到处追逐坏人？
You all tired, from chasing the bad
man all over the place?
不好意思....
Excuse me?
没有人欣赏你, 是吗？
Nobody appreciates
you, do they?
是吗？
Do they?
拜托, 他是个坏马
Oh come on, he's a bad horse.
哦, 它只不过是一只个头大的宝贝
Oh, he's nothing but
a big sweetheart.
是不是啊？
Isn't that right?
马克西姆斯
Maximus.
你在开我玩笑
You've got to be
kidding me.
听着, 今天是我人生的大日子
Look, today is kinda the biggest day of my life.
而我希望, 我希望你不要逮捕他
And the thing is, I need you not to get him arrested.
只要二十四小时, 然后...
Just for twenty four hours and then,
你想怎么追, 就怎么追他 ....
you can chase each other to
your hearts content.
好吗?
Okay?
而且今天是我的生日, 麻烦你多考虑一下.
And it's also my birthday.
Just so you know.
喔 很抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
这是要给失踪的公主
It's for the lost Princess.
鞠躬谢幕吧
To the boats
嘿 马克斯
Hey, Max.
怎么啦？我买的啦
What? I brought them.
大多数是买的
Most of them.
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
那么, 你人生中 最美好的一天,
Well, best day of your life.
我想你应该有一个 像样点的座位
I figured you should have
a decent seat.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我吓坏了
I'm terrified.
为什么呢?
Why?
我一直望着窗外.... 十八年了
I've been looking out the
window for eighteen years.
梦想着, 当我亲眼看到那些灯升空时, 会是什么感觉..
Dreaming about what it would feel
like when those lights rise in the sky.
如果它不是我 梦想的那样呢？
What if it's not everything
that I dreamed it would be?
会是的 ..
It will be.
如果它不是呢？我要怎么做呢 ??
And what if it is? What will I do then?
那也是件好事, 我想
Well that's the good part,
I guess.
你可以去追寻一个新的梦想
You get to go find a new dream.
*所有从窗户看的那些日子*
*All those days
Watching from the windows.*
*这些年都在望着外面的世界*
*All those years
Outside looking in*
*我一直, 从来不知道*
*All that time
Never even knowing*
*我过去多盲目, 直到我来这里*
*Just how blind I've been
Now I'm here*
*星光闪烁中, 现在我在这里*
*Blinking in the starlight
Now I'm here*
*突然, 我看到, 站在这里看到*
*Suddenly I see
Standing here*
*它是, 哦, 如此清晰, 我终于来到此地*
*It's oh, so clear
I'm where I'm meant to be*
*终于, 我看到灯光, 它就像浓雾已经消散*
*And at last, I see the light
And it's like the fog has lifted*
*终于, 我看到灯光, 像天空焕然一新*
*And at last, I see the light
And it's like the sky is new*
*如此温暖, 光明和真实, 整个世界都改变了*
*And it's warm and real and bright
And the world has somehow shifted*
*所有的一切, 看起来都不同了*
*All at once
Everything looks different*
*自从, 我遇见了你*
*Now that I see you*
我也有东西要给你
I have something for you, too.
我早应该把它给你了, 但我只是害怕
I should have given it to you
before, but I was just scared.
而事实是, 我不再害怕了
And the thing is,I'm not scared anymore.
你知道我是什么意思？
You know what I mean?
也让我说
I'm starting to.
*所有那些追逐白日梦的日子*
*All those days
Chasing down a daydream*
*这些年来活的浑浑噩噩*
*All those years
Living in a blur*
*从来不曾 真正明白*
*All that time
Never truly seeing*
*人生的意义, 直到遇见了她*
*Things, the way they were
Now she's here*
星光闪耀中  终于, 遇见了她*
*Shining in the starlight
Now she's here*
*突然, 我知道 只要她在身边*
*Suddenly I know
If she's here*
*我人生的方向, 突然变得清澈*
*It's crystal clear
I'm where I'm meant to go*
*终于, 我看到了光明*
*And at last, I see the light*
*它就像浓雾已经消散*
*And it's like the fog has lifted*
*终于, 我看到了光明*
*And at last, I see the light*
*它就像天空 焕然一新*
*And it's like the sky is new*
*如此温暖, 光明和真实, 整个世界都改变了*
*And it's warm and real and bright
And the world has somehow shifted*
*所有的一切, 看起来都不同了*
*All at once
Everything is different*
*自从, 我遇见了你*
*Now that I, see you.*
*Now that I... see you.*
你没事吧？
Is everything okay?
咦？哦, 没事
Huh? Oh yes.
嗯, 是的, 当然
Uh, yes of course.
我只是...
I just...
对不起, 一切都很好
I'm sorry, everything is fine.
只是还有件事, 我一定要去处理
There's just something I
have to take care of.
好..
Okay.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
没事的, 帕斯卡
It's all right, Pascal.
啊, 你们在这儿
Ahh, there you are.
我一直在到处寻找你们, 自从我们走散了
I've been searching everywhere for
you guys. Since we got separated.
嘿, 新鬓角修得不错, 是吧？
Hey the sideburns are coming
in nice, huh?
你一定很引以为傲
You gotta be excited about that.
总之, 只是想说, 我当初不应该溜走,
王冠归你们了 ..
Anyhow, just wanted to say, I shouldn't have split.
The crown is all yours.
我会想念你们, 但我认为这样...最好
I'll miss you, but I think
its for the... best.
又想瞒着我们吗？   嘿, 莱德？
Holding out on us again?
Hey, Ryder?
什么？, 我们听说你发现了什么
What? We heard you found something.
比一顶王冠 更有价值的东西
Something much more valuable than a crown.
我们要她来.. 代替王冠
We want her, instead.
我还以为你带着我的王冠跑了
I was starting to think you
ran off with the crown and left me.
他是跑了
He did.
什么？不会的
What?
No.
他不会的
He wouldn't.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
尤金？
Eugene?
尤金！
Eugene!
公平交易
Fair trade.
用一顶王冠, 换来拥有魔法头发的女孩
A crown, for the girl
with the magic hair.
你认为人们会为青春永驻, 付多少钱给我？
How much do you think someone
will pay to stay young and healthy forever?
不, 拜托
No, please.
不
NO!
长发姑娘！
Rapunzel!
妈妈？
Mother?
哦, 我的宝贝女孩
Oh, my precious girl.
母亲
Mother.
你没事吧？ 你受伤了吗？
Are you all right? Are you hurt?
-母亲, 你是怎么...
-我很担心你, 亲爱的
- Mother, how did you?
- I was so worried about
you dear.
所以我跟着你
So I followed you.
然后我看见他们攻击你
And I saw them attack you.
走吧, 走吧, 他们快醒了.
All right, let's go, let's go
before they come to.
你是对的, 妈妈
You were right, mother.
你一切都是对的
You were right about everything.
我知道, 亲爱的
I know darling.
我知道
I know.
你看！
Look!
王冠
The crown.
长发姑娘
Rapunzel.
长发姑娘！
RAPUNZEL!
不, 不 等, 等等, 等一下 伙计们, 伙计们
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.Guys, guys.
长发姑娘！
Rapunzel!
让我们做个了断, 莱德
Let's get this over with, Ryder.
我们去哪儿？
Where are we going?
什么都没发生的, 好吗 ...
There, it never happened.
现在, 洗手吃晚饭吧
Now, wash up for dinner.
我正在煮榛子果仁汤
I'm making hazel nut soup.
我真的试过, 长发姑娘
I really did try, Rapunzel.
我试图警告你, 外头究竟是怎样
I tried to warn you,what was out there.
世界是黑暗的, 自私,
The world is dark, and selfish,
和残忍的
and cruel.
哪怕我们拥有一丁点的光明
If it finds even the slightest ray of sunshine.
都会被破坏
It destroys it.
你怎会知道她的事情的？
How did you know about her?
告诉我, 马上！
Tell me, now!
这不是我们做的
It wasn't us.
是那个老太太
It was the old lady.
老太太？
Old lady?
等等, 不, 等等！
Wait, no, wait!
你不明白, 她有麻烦了
You don't understand,
she's in trouble.
等一等…
Wait!
长发姑娘？
Rapunzel?
长发姑娘, 怎么回事了？
Rapunzel, what's going on up there?
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我就是失踪的公主...
I'm the lost princess.
请大声说, 长发姑娘,
你知道我讨厌喃喃自语
Oh, please, speak up, Rapunzel.
You know how I hate the mumbling.
我就是失踪的公主
I am the lost Princess.
不是吗？
Aren't I?
听清楚了吗, 妈妈？
Did I mumble, Mother?
或者我不该这么称呼你？
Or should I even call you that?
哦, 长发姑娘, 你知道自己在说什么吗？
Oh, Rapunzel, do you even hear yourself?
为什么你会问 这样一个可笑的问题？
Why would you ask such
a ridiculous question?
是你！这都是你
It was you!
It was all, you.
我做的一切, 是为了保护你
Everything I did, was to protect you.
-长发姑娘,
-我的整个人生
- Rapunzel.
- I spent my entire life,
把自己藏起来, 不让别人用我的魔力
Hiding from people who
would use me for my power.
-长发姑娘！,
-其实, 我应该躲着的人 ...
- Rapunzel!
- And I should have been hiding.
就是你
From you.
你去哪里？
Where will you go?
他不会等你的
He won't be there for you.
你对他做了什么？
What did you do to him?
以他的罪行, 会被吊死
That criminal, is to
be hanged for his crimes.
-不,
-现在, 现在都没事了,
- No.
- Now, now. It's all right.
听我说
Listen to me.
所有这一切 是理所应当的
All of this is as
it should be.
不
NO!
你看错了这个世界
You were wrong about the world.
而你看错了我
And you were wrong about me.
我永远不会再让你利用我的头发！
And I will never let you
use my hair, again!
你要我变成坏人？
You want me to be the bad guy?
“好的”
Fine.
现在我是坏人了
Now I'm the bad, guy.
这是啥情形？
What's this?
把门打开
Open up.
通关密语？
What's the password?
-"什么"？
-答错了
- What?
- Nope.
打开此门
Open this door.
错得离谱呢
Not even close.
你有三秒钟
You have three seconds
一...
One...
二...
Two...
三...
Three...
平底锅, 可是秘密武器, 对不对？
Frying pans.Who knew, right?
-头向下 !
-好的, 头向下
- Head down?
- Head down.
-手臂夹紧,
-好, 手臂夹紧
- Arms in?
- Arms in.
-膝盖分开
-膝盖分开 ...
- Knees apart?
- Knees apart.
双膝分开？
Knees apart?
为什么 双膝要分 ...
Why do I need to keep my
knees apar...
马克斯！
Max.
是你带他们来这里的？
You brought them here?
谢谢你
Thank you.
真的, 谢谢你
No really, thank you.
嗯, 我觉得, 我们一直都相互误解着
Uh, I feel maybe this whole time
we've just misunderstanding one another.
而我们只是...
你是对的... 我们快走
And we're really just, yeah
your right. We should go.
马克斯！
Max.
Max!
好吧, 马克斯, 让我看看你可以跑多快
Okay Max, lets see how
fast you can run.
长发姑娘
Rapunzel.
长发姑娘, 放下你的头发
Rapunzel, let down your hair.
长发姑娘, 我以为我再也见不到你了
Rapunzel, I thought I'd never
see you again.
看看你逼我做了什么事, 长发姑娘
Now look what you've done,
Rapunzel.
哦, 别担心, 亲爱的
Oh don't worry, dear.
他死了, 我们的秘密才能守住
Our secret will die with him.
至于我们呢？
And as for us?
我们去的地方, 再也没有人会找到你...
We are going where no one
will ever find you, again.
长发姑娘, 真的, 够了 ...
Rapunzel, really.
Enough all ready.
停止抗拒我...
Stop fighting me.
不！我不会停止
NO! I won't stop.
我的余生的每一分钟, 我都会拚力对抗
For every minute of the rest
of my life I will fight.
我永远不会停止 尝试摆脱你
I will never stop trying
to get away from you.
除非, 你现在让我去救他...
But, if you let me save him...
我就跟你一起去...
I will go with you.
不..不, 长发姑娘
No. No, Rapunzel.
我不会跑, 我永远也不会跑
I'll never run, I'll never
try to escape.
只要让我医治他, 我会和你在一起
Just let me heal him. And
you and I will be together.
永远, 就像你想要的
Forever, just like you want.
一切都会像以前一样
Everything will be the way it was.
我保证
I promise.
就像你想要的
Just like you want.
只要让我医治他
Just... let me... heal him.
这是要防着你 等会偷偷跟踪我们 ..
In case you get any ideas
about following us.
尤 ...尤金！
Eu..Eugene!
哦, 我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
-你会没事的, 只要一下子
-不, 长发姑娘！
- Everything is going to okay, though.
- No, Rapunzel!
-我保证, 你要相信我
-不...
- I promise, you have to trust me.
- No..
-来, 深呼吸,
-我不能让你...这样做
- Come on.
- I can't let you do this.
而且...我不能让你死
And I can't let you die.
-但是, 如果你这样做
But if you do this.
-你也...会死
-嘿
- Then you... will die.
- Hey.
没事的
It's gonna be all right.
长发姑娘, 等一 ...
Rapunzel, wait...
尤金, 为什么 ...？
Eugene, what...?
不要！
NOOO!
不 ..不！
No... NO!
你做了什么？你做了什么！
What have you done?WHAT HAVE YOU DONE!
不要！
No, no, no,
NOOO!
不！不, 不, 不, 不
No, no, no, noooo.
不, 不, 不, 不, 尤金
NO! Noooooooooo! No, no, no, no, Eugene.
哦, 看看我, 看看我, 我就在这儿
Oh, look at me, look me,
I'm right here.
不要走, 留在我身边, 尤金
Don't go, stay with me, Eugene.
*花儿, 闪亮和发光, 让你的力量闪耀*
*Flower gleam and glow,
Let your powers shine*
*使时光倒转, 带回曾经的我*
*Make the clock reverse,
bring back what once was mine.*
长发姑娘？ 什么？
- Rapunzel...
- What?
你是我 新的 "梦想"
You were my new dream.
而 你也是我的
And you were mine.
*治愈了所有伤害*
*Heal what has been hurt.*
*改变命运的设计*
*Change the fates design.*
*挽回已经失去的*
*Save what has been lost.*
*带回曾经的我*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
*曾经是 我的*
What once was mine.
长发姑娘？
Rapunzel?
尤金
Eugene.
我有没有告诉过你, 我特别喜欢黑发姑娘？
Did I ever tell you, I've
got a thing for brunettes?
恩, 你可以想像, 接下来发生的事情
Well, you could imagine what
happened next.
王国欢欣鼓舞
The kingdom rejoiced.
因为失踪的公主回来了
For the lost Princess had returned.
狂欢持续了整整一个星期
The party lasted an entire week.
而且, 老实说, 我不太记得细节
And, honestly I don't
remember much of it.
所有的人都 梦想成真
Dreams came true
all over the place.
那家伙后来成为世界上最有名的, 音乐会的钢琴演奏家
That guy went on to become the
most famous concert pianist in the world,
if you can believe it.
这家伙？嗯, 他终于找到了真爱
And this guy? Well he eventually
found true love.
至于这家伙, 嗯, 我猜他很快乐
As for this guy, well,
I assume he's happy.
我是没听他抱怨过啦
He's never told me otherwise.
感谢马克西姆斯, 王国的犯罪, 几乎在一夜之间消失
Thanks to Maximus, crime in the kingdom
disappeared almost over night.
大部分的苹果.. 也消失了
As did most of the apples.
帕斯卡呢, 从来没有改变过
Pascal? Never changed.
最后长发姑娘回到家了,
At last Rapunzel was home,
她终于有了一个真正的家庭
and she finally had a real family.
她是一个值得等待的公主
She was a Princess worth
waiting for.
所有的人爱她, 她带领她的王国
Beloved by all, she led her kingdom
以她所有的恩典和智慧, 就像她的父母一样
with all the grace and wisdom that
her parents did before her.
至于我呢
And as for me, well.
我名字改回 "尤金", 重新做人.
I started going by Eugene again.
停止偷窃, 基本上改头换面了
Stopped thieving, and basically
turned it all around.
但我知道, 大家都想问的问题...
But I know what the big question is.
长发姑娘, 会和我结婚吗？
Did Rapunzel and I ever get married?
嗯, 我很高兴地告诉你
Well I'm pleased to tell you.
一年又一年, 她不断的向我求婚,
That after years, and years of asking,
一直求我, 一直求 .....
and asking, and asking.
我终于答应了
I finally said yes.
*尤金*
*Eugene*
好吧, 其实.. 是我求婚啦
All right, I asked her.
我们从此过着 幸福快乐的生活
And we're living happily ever after.
是的, 我们会的
Yes, we are.
至于我呢
All right, I asked her.
我名字改回 "尤金", 重新做人.
And we're living happily ever after.
停止偷窃, 基本上改头换面了
Yes, we are.
EVILZRR
----FOR THE FIRST TIME TO MAKE A SUBTITLE-----